<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<django-objects version="1.0"><object model="collector.rite" pk="Baptism of Fire"><field name="code" type="CharField">Baptism of Fire (1)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">Mystic Rite</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">1</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="description" type="TextField">Most tribes attempt to track down all children born to their Kinfolk within one month of the children's birth to see if they "share the blood." Those who are Garou are "baptized" in the light of their auspice moon, beside a rite fire. Such a baptism most commonly involves mingling ashes with a few drops of Garou blood; the mixture is then touched to the child's ears, nose, eyelids, and tongue. In the presence of one of the lesser tribal spirits, known as a Kin-Fetch, the babe is then held up to the moonlight while the baptizing Garou howls Gaia's greeting to the newborn. The ritemaster then has the Kin-Fetch kiss the infant. The spirit's fiery kiss inscribes a spiritual brand upon the babe in the form of the newborn's tribal pictograph. This mark is not visible on the newborn's body; the only mark left is spiritual. It is impossible to remove this spiritual brand. Such a mark can be traced and recognized by all Garou (including the Black Spiral Dancers, who all too often track down cubs of other tribes and capture them in order to create more of their foul number). The participating Kin-Fetch spirit is assigned to watch over the young Garou as she grows to maturity, so that the tribe may always know the child's location and whether she is endangered. When the child is about to undergo the First Change and is ready for the Rite of Passage, the spirit alerts the tribe. Unfortunately, minor spirits are notoriously weak-willed and easily distracted. All too often a Kin-Fetch loses track of its charge or becomes lost itself, leaving the young cub on her own. Such "lost cubs" often become Lunatics or recluses, terrified of themselves and unable to understand their powerful primal urges.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">The ritemaster makes a Cha+Rituals roll (difficulty 6). Only one success is required, but additional successes imrove the chance the kin-fetch will keep trakc of the child. This rite must be performed at nightunder the moon in which the child was born. Although this rite is normally performed within the month of the birth, the brand can be inscribed at any time before the cub reaches adolescence and undergoes her First Change.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Bone Rhythms"><field name="code" type="CharField">Bone Rhythms (0)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">minor</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">0</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="description" type="TextField">This rite is performed in homage of the Garou's totem spirit. Each spirit has a different rhythm connected to it, and the Garou taps out this rhythm with special drumsticks to honor her totem. Such "sticks" are traditionally made of bone, but can be fashioned from any material.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Any garou who performs this rite three times per day for at least three consecutive days gains an additional die to any roll while in the spirit Realms. Once this die is used, the Garou must rebuild the energies for additional three days before regaining the extra die.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Breath of Gaia"><field name="code" type="CharField">Breath of Gaia (0)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">minor</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">0</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="description" type="TextField">During this rite the Garou breathes deeply of Gaia breath (air) 13 times. While so breathing, the Garou clears her mind of all things save her love of Gaia.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">The Garou must perform this rite at least once per day for one full cycle of the moon. So doing enables the Garou to lower by 2 the difficulty level of any one healing or detection roll.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Gaia's Vengeful Teeth"><field name="code" type="CharField">Gaia's Vengeful Teeth (5)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">punishment</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">5</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="description" type="TextField"></field><field name="system" type="TextField"></field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Gathering of the Departed"><field name="code" type="CharField">Gathering of the Departed (1)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">Rite of Death</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">1</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="description" type="TextField">This rite is enacted in honor of the newly dead. A Galliard or a packmate of the departed werewolf usually performs the rite. The specifics of the rite vary dramatically from tribe to tribe. For example, a Fianna ritemaster leads the sept in the telling of tales, both raucous and heroic, about the fallen Garou. In contrast stands the Wendigo’s solemn rite in which the ritemaster and all the fallen one’s packmates stand on the highest peak available, tails to the wind, and howl out their pride and grief to speed their companion onward to her next life. The exact form of the rite is less important than the acknowledgment it represents.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">The ritemaster leads the release of the Garou’s combined emotions into the spirit world. At the Storyteller’s discretion, this rite may make the deceased’s spirit easier to contact through the Ancestors Background.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Greet the Moon"><field name="code" type="CharField">Greet the Moon (0)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">Minor Rite</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">0</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="description" type="TextField">This rite is an exuberant paean to Luna. During this rite, the Garou howls an elaborate greeting to the moon. This greeting varies with the phase of the moon.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Performing this rite each night at moonrise for a full phase of the moon enables the Garou to add one die to all social interactions with Garou of that phase's auspice the next time the moon reaches the phase in question.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Greet the Sun"><field name="code" type="CharField">Greet the Sun (0)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">Minor Rite</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">0</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="description" type="TextField">Certain Children of Gaia and a few Uktena and Wendigo practice this rite. It's similar to Green the Moon but is performed at sunrise.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">The Garou must sing Helios' praises for nine consecutive days. If the Garou does so, Helios grants his devotee an additional die when attempting to sense Wyrm creatures or Wyrm-taint, provided the Garou continues to sing his praises daily. If the Garou misses even one day, he must begin this rite anew to reap its benefits.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Hunting Prayer"><field name="code" type="CharField">Hunting Prayer (0)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">Minor Rite</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">0</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="description" type="TextField">This common rite takes many forms, but it always involves pausing before the start of a hunt to praise Gaia and all her creatures. In addition, the Garou chooses some item to hold her prayers. This item can range from an old belt to a tooth, but the werewolf must have it with her when she hunts. If she loses the item, she must choose another item and start her prayers anew.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">If a Garou performs this rite before every hunt for three turnings of the moon, she receives an additional die to all tracking rolls so long as she continues her pre-hunt prayers. If she hunts even once without praying, she must renew her prayers for another three months before again receiving the bonus.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Moot Rite"><field name="code" type="CharField">Moot Rite (1)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">caern</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">1</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="description" type="TextField">A moot cannot open until this rite is completed, recharging the caern with Gnosis. The rite always includes a prolonged howl led by a werewolf known as the Master of the Howl. This howl varies by tribe and sept, but always expresses the unique nature of the sept. All werewolves present must form a circle within the caern itself before they commence howling. Numerous variations on the basic requirements exist: The Red Talons often bite their paws and scratch blood into the earth, while Uktena pass their most powerful fetish from one to another as each in turn adds her voice to the howl. However it is done, the howl must echo forth and the eternal circle must form.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Max Gnosis (diff 7)  The rite must be performed at least once per month to keep the caern consecrated. During the course of a moot, the participants must empower the caern with a combined total of five Gnosis points per caern level in order to replenish it fully.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Prayer for the Prey"><field name="code" type="CharField">Prayer for the Prey (0)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">Minor Rite</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">0</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="description" type="TextField">A specific form of the Rite of Contrition, this rite involves the werewolf stepping sideways into the Umbra just after making a kill, subsequently thanking the spirit of the prey for giving its own life that the Garou might survive. Performing this rite is a sign of respect to Gaia, her children, and life itself.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">The character must perform this rite upon every beast of Gaia (not including Wyrm-spawn) he slays for one full turning of the moon. Should this be done, all of her difficulty numbers drop by one when dealing with Nature-spirits. This bonus lasts until she kills without taking time to thank the creature's spirit.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of Accomplishment"><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of Accomplishment (2)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">renown</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">2</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="description" type="TextField"></field><field name="system" type="TextField"></field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of Becoming"><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of Becoming (2)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">mystic</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">2</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="description" type="TextField"></field><field name="system" type="TextField"></field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of Binding"><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of Binding (1)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">mystic</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">1</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="description" type="TextField"></field><field name="system" type="TextField"></field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of Caern Building"><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of Caern Building (5)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">caern</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">5</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="description" type="TextField"></field><field name="system" type="TextField"></field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of Cleansing"><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of Cleansing (1)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">Rite of Accord</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">1</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="description" type="TextField">This rite purifies a person, place or object, allowing it to be used without fear of contamination by the Wyrm. To perform this rite the Garou must inscribe a circle on the earth, walking widdershins (counterclockwise) around the afflicted person(s) or object(s) while holding a smoldering branch or torch. She must use a branch (preferably willow or birch) dipped in pure water or snow to asperge the object or person cleansed. As this is done, all Garou present release an eerie, otherworldly howl in an attempt to "frighten away" and this banish the corrupting influence. Ideally, this rite is performed at dawn, but it can be performed at any time.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">This rite can be cast upon more than one person or object, but the leader must spend one Gnosis point on each extra thing or person in need of cleansing. The difficulty level equals the Gnosis of the spirit that inflicetedthe contagion (maximum difficulty 10). Only one success is required. If the rite is performed at dawn, the difficulty level of the rite is reduced by one. Note that this rite cannot heal wounds or damage caused by contamination. It only removes any existing contamination. [Cha+Rituals]</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of Contrition"><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of Contrition (1)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">Rite of Accord</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">1</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="description" type="TextField">This rite is a form of apology used to prevent the enmity of spirits or Garou whom an individual has annoyed, or to prevent war between septs or tribes. The rite most often involves the enactor dropping to her belly and sliding forward. The ritemaster may also whine and lick his paws or hands. If performed well, however, a simple inclination of the head may suffice. To enact this rite successfully, the Garou must either give a small gift to the offended individual or, in the case of a spirit, possess some aspect of the spirit in question (for example, a clay falcon if the Garou is appealing to the totem spirit Falcon).</field><field name="system" type="TextField">The difficulty level of the rite equals the Rage of the target spirit or werewolf. A single success suffices for a gracious apology, but may not be enough to mend friendships or forgive grievous errors. The more successes, the greater the wrong that can be forgiven. Werewolves who refuse to recognize a Rite of Contrition are looked upon badly by elders. Most spirits will always accept a well-performed rite. This effect lasts until the Garou performs another action that could harm or insult the other.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of Keres"><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of Keres (4)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">seasonal</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">4</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="description" type="TextField"></field><field name="system" type="TextField"></field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of Ostracism"><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of Ostracism (2)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">punishment</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">2</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="description" type="TextField"></field><field name="system" type="TextField"></field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of Passage"><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of Passage (2)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">renown</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">2</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="description" type="TextField"></field><field name="system" type="TextField"></field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of Reawakening"><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of Reawakening (2)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">seasonal</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">2</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="description" type="TextField"></field><field name="system" type="TextField"></field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of Renunciation"><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of Renunciation (1)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">accord</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">1</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="description" type="TextField"></field><field name="system" type="TextField"></field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of Spirit Awakening"><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of Spirit Awakening (2)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">mystic</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">2</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="description" type="TextField"></field><field name="system" type="TextField"></field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of Talisman Dedication"><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of Talisman Dedication (1)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">Mystic Rite</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">1</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="description" type="TextField">This common rite allows a werewolf to bind objects to her body, allowing them to fit her various forms (jeans will grow to accommodate the Crinos form rather than splitting at the seams, for example) and accompany the Garou into the Umbra. Such talismans are most commonly mundane items, for spiritual items such as fetishes and talens remain with the werewolf in all forms and in the Umbra automatically. A werewolf most often performs this rite during the phase of the moon under which she was born. Each auspice has its own peculiar ritual.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">The cost is one Gnosis point per object dedicated, and a character may never have more objects bound to himself than his Gnosis score. Conceptually linked groups of objects may count as a single object as the Storyteller’s discretion. For example, as a set of clothing would be considered one object rather than one shirt, one pair of pants, two socks, and so on; or a box of ammunition might be dedicated to the character, rather than requiring one dedication per bullet.
Objects will generally resize themselves to accommodate the character’s various forms (such as a backpack’s straps lengthening to accommodate Crinos form), but may simply meld with the character in forms where they can be of no use — for example, a knife may become a knife-shaped tattoo in Hispo. Others must spend a point of Willpower to attempt to steal dedicated objects from the werewolf. [Wits+Rituals]</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of Wounding"><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of Wounding (1)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">Rite of Renown</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">1</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="description" type="TextField">This rite celebrates a Garou’s first battle wound. Each tribe marks this moment differently, but all honor this sign of courage. Many tribes rub ash into at least part of the wound to form a scar of remembrance. The Get of Fenris always end this rite with a fierce all-night revel filled with drinking and fighting. By contrast, the Children of Gaia end their Rites of Wounding with prayers for peace and understanding among all creatures.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Only the wounded character and the ritemaster must be present for this rite, although the werewolf’s pack and sept are normally present. The wounded character receives two points of Glory if this rite succeeds.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of the Fetish"><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of the Fetish (3)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">mystic</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">3</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="description" type="TextField"></field><field name="system" type="TextField"></field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of the Opened Bridge"><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of the Opened Bridge (4)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">caern</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">4</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="description" type="TextField"></field><field name="system" type="TextField"></field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of the Opened Caern"><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of the Opened Caern (1)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">Caern Rite</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">1</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="description" type="TextField">Each caern has a specific power associated with it, generally of a beneficial nature. Thus, there are caerns of Rage, caerns of Gnosis, Strength, Enigmas, and so on. If a character is knowledgeable enough, she may tap into the caern’s power and use it herself. Doing so is commonly known as “opening” a caern. Such a feat shouldn’t be attempted lightly — Gaia’s sacred places don’t give up their power easily, and failure to harness such power can seriously harm the Garou.

Each caern has its own requirements of the ritemaster. In order to open a caern of Enigmas, a Garou might walk a spiral path while calling out the Greek myth of Persephone; to open a caern of Rage, the Garou might change into Crinos and chant the litany of his ancestors who have fallen in battle against the Wyrm. The key is forging a connection to the particular spirit of the caern.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">To open a caern, the character engages in a resisted, extended test of Wits + Rituals (difficulty 7) against the caern’s spirit, seeking to gain a number of successes equal to the caern’s level. The caern spirit uses the caern’s level as its dice pool (difficulty of the ritemaster’s Gnosis), seeking to gain (Ritemaster’s Willpower) successes. The first party to reach their target number of successes triumphs. If the character wins the test, she can add the caern’s rating to her dice pool when performing actions appropriate to the caern’s focus. If she loses, she takes lethal damage equal to the number of successes by which the caern beat her; a botch makes this damage aggravated.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of the Questing Stone"><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of the Questing Stone (1)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">mystic</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">1</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="description" type="TextField">This rite allows the werewolf to find a person or object (but not a location). She must know the name of the object or individual, and must dangle a stone or needle from a thread while concentrating on the item or person sought. Glass Walkers often use maps and substitute a
compass for the traditional stone and thread.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Wits + Rituals (diff 7). If the Garou has a piece of the item or individual (a clipping of hair, a piece of cloth) the difficulty drops by one. The werewolf gains only a sense of the object’s general location, not its exact position.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of the Shrouded Glen"><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of the Shrouded Glen (4)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">caern</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">4</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="description" type="TextField"></field><field name="system" type="TextField"></field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of the Totem"><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of the Totem (3)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">mystic</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">3</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="description" type="TextField"></field><field name="system" type="TextField"></field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of the Winter Winds"><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of the Winter Winds (2)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">seasonal</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">2</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="description" type="TextField"></field><field name="system" type="TextField"></field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of the Winter Wolf"><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of the Winter Wolf (3)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">death</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">3</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="description" type="TextField"></field><field name="system" type="TextField"></field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Satire Rite"><field name="code" type="CharField">Satire Rite (3)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">mystic</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">3</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="description" type="TextField"></field><field name="system" type="TextField"></field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Stone of Scorn"><field name="code" type="CharField">Stone of Scorn (2)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">punishment</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">2</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="description" type="TextField"></field><field name="system" type="TextField"></field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="The Badger's Burrow"><field name="code" type="CharField">The Badger's Burrow (4)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">caern</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">4</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="description" type="TextField"></field><field name="system" type="TextField"></field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="The Great Hunt"><field name="code" type="CharField">The Great Hunt (2)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">seasonal</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">2</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="description" type="TextField"></field><field name="system" type="TextField"></field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="The Hunt"><field name="code" type="CharField">The Hunt (3)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">punishment</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">3</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="description" type="TextField"></field><field name="system" type="TextField"></field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="The Rending of the Veil"><field name="code" type="CharField">The Rending of the Veil (4)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">punishment</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">4</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="description" type="TextField"></field><field name="system" type="TextField"></field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Voice of the Jackal"><field name="code" type="CharField">Voice of the Jackal (2)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">punishment</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">2</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="description" type="TextField"></field><field name="system" type="TextField"></field></object></django-objects>