<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<django-objects version="1.0"><object model="collector.archetype" pk="Architect"><field name="source" type="CharField">VTM3</field><field name="description" type="TextField">The Architect has a sense of purpose even greater than herself. She is truly happy only when creating something of lasting value for others. People will always need things, and the Architect strives to provide at least one necessity. Inventors, pioneers, town founders,  entrepreneurs and the like are all Architect Archetypes.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Regain a point of Willpower whenever you establish something of importance or lasting value.</field></object><object model="collector.archetype" pk="Autocrat"><field name="source" type="CharField">VTM3</field><field name="description" type="TextField">The Autocrat wants to be in charge. He seeks prominence for its own sake, not because he has an operation’s best interests at heart or because he has the best ideas (though he may certainly think so). He may genuinely believe others are incompetent, but ultimately he craves power and control. Dictators, gang leaders, bullies, corporate raiders and their ilk are Autocrat Archetypes.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Regain a point of Willpower when you achieve control over a group or organization involving other individuals.</field></object><object model="collector.archetype" pk="Bon Vivant"><field name="source" type="CharField">VTM3</field><field name="description" type="TextField">The Bon Vivant knows that life — and unlife — is shallow and meaningless. As such, the Bon Vivant decides to enjoy her time on Earth. The Bon Vivant is not necessarily irresponsible.
Rather, she is simply predisposed to having a good time along the way. Most Bon Vivants have low Self-Control scores, as they are so given to excess. Hedonists, sybarites and dilettantes are
all examples of the Bon Vivant Archetype.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Regain a point of Willpower whenever you truly enjoy yourself and can fully express your exultation. At the Storyteller’s option, a particularly fabulous revelry may yield multiple
Willpower points.</field></object><object model="collector.archetype" pk="Bravo"><field name="source" type="CharField">VTM3</field><field name="description" type="TextField">The Bravo is a tough and a bully, and often takes perverse pleasure in tormenting the weak. To the Bravo’s mind, might makes right; power is what matters, and only those with power should be respected. Naturally, physical power is the best kind, but any kind will do. The Bravo sees overt threats as a perfectly reasonable means of gaining cooperation. The Bravo is not incapable of pity or kindness, he just prefers to do things his way. Robbers, bigots, thugs and the insecure are all Bravo Archetypes.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Regain a point of Willpower any time you achieve your agenda through brutishness or intimidation. This need not be physical, as many Bravos verbally or socially cow their victims.</field></object><object model="collector.archetype" pk="Caregiver"><field name="source" type="CharField">VTM3</field><field name="description" type="TextField">Everyone needs comfort, a shoulder to cry on. A Caregiver takes her comfort in consoling others, and people often come to her with their problems. Vampires with Caregiver Archetypes
often attempt, as best they may, to protect the mortals on whom they feed. Nurses, doctors and psychiatrists are examples of potential Caregivers.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Regain a point of Willpower whenever you successfully protect or nurture someone else.</field></object><object model="collector.archetype" pk="Celebrant"><field name="source" type="CharField">VTM3</field><field name="description" type="TextField">The Celebrant takes joy in her cause. Whether the character’s passion is battle, religious fervor, foiling her rivals or reading fine literature, it gives the Celebrant the strength to withstand adversity. Given the chance, the Celebrant will indulge in her passion as deeply
as possible. Unlike the Fanatic (p. 114), the Celebrant pursues her passion not out of duty, but out of enthusiasm. Crusaders, hippies, political activists and art enthusiasts are Celebrant Archetypes.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Regain a point of Willpower whenever you pursue your cause or convert another character to the same passion. Conversely, lose a point of temporary Willpower whenever you are denied your passion or it is badly lost to you.</field></object><object model="collector.archetype" pk="Child"><field name="source" type="CharField">VTM3</field><field name="description" type="TextField">The Child is still immature in personality and temperament. He wants what he wants now, and often prefers someone to give it to him. Although he can typically care for himself, he would
rather have a caretaker-type cater to his bratty desires. Some Child Archetypes are actually innocent rather than immature, ignorant of the cold ways of the real world. Children, spoiled
individuals and some drug abusers are Child Archetypes.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Regain a point of Willpower whenever you manage to convince someone to help you with no gain to herself, or to nurture you.</field></object><object model="collector.archetype" pk="Competitor"><field name="source" type="CharField">VTM3</field><field name="description" type="TextField">The Competitor takes great excitement in the pursuit of victory. To the Competitor, every task is a new challenge to meet and a new contest to win. Indeed, the Competitor sees all interactions as some sort of opportunity for her to be the best — the best leader, the most productive, the most valuable or whatever. Corporate raiders, professional athletes and impassioned researchers are all examples of Competitor Archetypes.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Regain one point of Willpower whenever you succeed at a test or challenge. Especially difficult victories may, at the Storyteller’s discretion, allow you to regain multiple Willpower points.</field></object><object model="collector.archetype" pk="Conformist"><field name="source" type="CharField">VTM3</field><field name="description" type="TextField">The Conformist is a follower, taking another’s lead and finding security in the decisions of others. She prefers not to take charge, instead seeking to throw in with the rest of the group and lend her own unique aid. The Conformist is drawn to the most dynamic personality or the individual she perceives to be the “best.” Being a Conformist is not necessarily a bad thing — every group needs followers to lend stability to their causes. Groupies, party voters and “the masses” are Conformist Archetypes.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Regain a point of Willpower whenever the group achieves one of its goals due to your support.</field></object><object model="collector.archetype" pk="Conniver"><field name="source" type="CharField">VTM3</field><field name="description" type="TextField">Why work for something when you can trick somebody else into getting it for you? The Conniver always tries to find the easy way, the fast track to success and wealth. Some people
call him a thief, a swindler or less pleasant terms, but he knows that everybody in the world would do unto him if they could. He just does it first, and better. Criminals, con artists, salespeople, urchins and entrepreneurs might be Connivers.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Regain a point of Willpower whenever you trick someone into doing something for you.</field></object><object model="collector.archetype" pk="Curmudgeon"><field name="source" type="CharField">VTM3</field><field name="description" type="TextField">A Curmudgeon is bitter and cynical, finding flaws in everything and seeing little humor in life or unlife. He is often fatalistic or pessimistic, and has very little esteem for others. To the Curmudgeon, the glass is always half-full, though it may be damn near empty when other people are involved. Many elder vampires and Generation Xers are Curmudgeons.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Regain a point of Willpower whenever someone does something stupid, just like you said they would. You must predict this failure aloud (though you may simply whisper it to the Storyteller if you wish).</field></object><object model="collector.archetype" pk="Deviant"><field name="source" type="CharField">VTM3</field><field name="description" type="TextField">The Deviant is a freak, ostracized from society by unique tastes that place her outside the mainstream. Deviants are not indolent rebels or shiftless “unrecognized geniuses”; rather, they
are independent thinkers who don’t quite fit in the status quo. Deviant Archetypes often feel that the world stands against them, and as such reject traditional morality. Some have bizarre tastes, preferences and ideologies. Extremists, eccentric celebrities and straight-out weirdoes are Deviant Archetypes.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Regain a point of Willpower any time you are able to flout social mores without retribution.</field></object><object model="collector.archetype" pk="Director"><field name="source" type="CharField">VTM3</field><field name="description" type="TextField">To the Director, nothing is worse than chaos and disorder. The Director seeks to be in charge, adopting a “my way or the highway” attitude on matters of decision-making. The Director
is more concerned with bringing order out of strife, however, and need not be truly “in control” of a group to guide it. Coaches, teachers and many political figures exemplify the Director Archetype.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Regain a point of Willpower when you influence a group in the completion of a difficult task.</field></object><object model="collector.archetype" pk="Fanatic"><field name="source" type="CharField">VTM3</field><field name="description" type="TextField">The Fanatic has a purpose, and that purpose consumes his existence. The Fanatic pours himself into his cause; indeed, he may feel guilty for undertaking any objective that deviates from his higher goal. To the Fanatic, the end justifies the means — the cause is more important than those who serve it. Players who choose Fanatic Archetypes must select a cause for their character to further. Revolutionaries, zealots and sincere firebrands are all examples of Fanatic Archetypes.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Regain a point of Willpower whenever you accomplish some task that directly relates to your cause.</field></object><object model="collector.archetype" pk="Gallant"><field name="source" type="CharField">VTM3</field><field name="description" type="TextField">Gallants are flamboyant souls, always seeking attention and the chance to be the brightest stars. Gallants seek the company of others, if only to earn their adoration. Attention drives the
Gallant, and the chase is often as important as fulfilling that pursuit. Nothing excites a Gallant so much as a new audience to woo and win. Performers, only children and those with low self-esteem are often Gallant Archetypes.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Regain a Willpower point whenever you successfully impress another person. Ultimately, the Storyteller is the arbiter of when you dazzle someone, even in the case of other players’ characters.</field></object><object model="collector.archetype" pk="Judge"><field name="source" type="CharField">VTM3</field><field name="description" type="TextField">The Judge perpetually seeks to improve the system. A Judge takes pleasure in her rational nature and ability to draw the right conclusion when presented with facts. The Judge respects justice, as it is the most efficient model for resolving issues. Judges, while they pursue the “streamlining” of problems, are rarely visionary, as they prefer proven models to insight. Engineers, lawyers and doctors are often Judge Archetypes.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Regain a point of Willpower whenever you correctly deduce a mystery by assembling the clues presented, or when one of your arguments unites dissenting parties.</field></object><object model="collector.archetype" pk="Loner"><field name="source" type="CharField">VTM3</field><field name="description" type="TextField">Even in a crowd, the Loner sticks out, because he so obviously does not belong. Others view Loners as pariahs, remote and isolated, but in truth, the Loner prefers his own company to
that of others. For whatever reason, the Loner simply disdains others, and this feeling is often reciprocated. Criminals, radicals and free thinkers are all Loner Archetypes.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Regain a point of Willpower when you accomplish something by yourself, yet which still benefits the coterie in some way. For truly impressive success, or achievement in spite
of strong opposition, the Storyteller may choose to let you regain two Willpower points.</field></object><object model="collector.archetype" pk="Martyr"><field name="source" type="CharField">VTM3</field><field name="description" type="TextField">The Martyr suffers for his cause, enduring his trials out of the belief that his discomfort will ultimately improve others’ lot. Some Martyrs simply want the attention or sympathy their
ordeals engender, while others are sincere in their cause, greeting their opposition with unfaltering faith in their own beliefs. Many Inquisitors, staunch idealists and outcasts are Martyr Archetypes.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Regain a point of Willpower when you sacrifice yourself or your comfort for your ideals or another’s immediate gain.</field></object><object model="collector.archetype" pk="Masochist"><field name="source" type="CharField">VTM3</field><field name="description" type="TextField">The Masochist exists to test his limits, to see how much pain he can tolerate before he collapses. He gains satisfaction in humiliation, suffering, denial and even physical pain. The
Masochist defines who he is by his capacity to feel discomfort — he rises each night only to greet a new pain. Certain extreme athletes, urban tribalists and the clinically depressed exemplify the Masochist Archetype.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Regain two points of Willpower whenever you experience pain in a way you never have before.</field></object><object model="collector.archetype" pk="Monster"><field name="source" type="CharField">VTM3</field><field name="description" type="TextField">The Monster knows she is a creature of darkness and acts like it. Evil and suffering are the Monster’s tools, and she uses them wherever she goes. No villainy is below her; no hurt goes uninflicted and no lie remains untold. The Monster does not commit evil for its own sake, but rather as a means to understand what she has become. Many Sabbat, degenerate Kindred elders and unstable individuals display characteristics of the Monster Archetype.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Malignant deeds reinforce the Monster’s sense of purpose. Monster characters should pick a specific atrocity, regaining Willpower whenever they indulge that urge. For example, a tempter regains Willpower for luring someone into wickedness, while an apostate earns back Willpower for causing another to doubt her faith. Pick a destiny and fulfill it.</field></object><object model="collector.archetype" pk="Pedagogue"><field name="source" type="CharField">VTM3</field><field name="description" type="TextField">The Pedagogue knows it all, and desperately wants to inform others. Whether through a sense of purpose or a genuine desire to help others, the Pedagogue makes sure his message is heard
— at length, if necessary. Pedagogue Archetypes may range from well-meaning mentors to verbose blowhards who love to hear themselves talk. Instructors, the overeducated and “veterans of their field” are all examples of Pedagogue Archetypes.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Regain one point of Willpower whenever you see or learn of someone who has benefited from the wisdom you shared with them.</field></object><object model="collector.archetype" pk="Penitent"><field name="source" type="CharField">VTM3</field><field name="description" type="TextField">The Penitent exists to atone for the grave sin she commits simply by being who she is. Penitents have either low self-esteem or legitimate, traumatic past experiences, and feel compelled to “make up” for inflicting themselves upon the world. Penitent Archetypes are not always religious in outlook; some truly want to scourge the world of the grief they bring to it. Repentant sinners, persons with low self-esteem and remorseful criminals are examples of the Penitent Archetype.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Regain a point of Willpower whenever you feel that you have achieved absolution for a given grievance. This redemption should be of the same magnitude as the transgression — the
greater the crime, the greater the penance. The Storyteller is the ultimate arbiter of what constitutes a reasonable act of reparation.</field></object><object model="collector.archetype" pk="Perfectionist"><field name="source" type="CharField">VTM3</field><field name="description" type="TextField">Perfectionist Archetypes simply demand the best. A half-hearted job gives the Perfectionist no satisfaction, and she expects the same degree of commitment and attention to detail from others that she demands from herself. Although the Perfec-tionist may be strict and exacting, the achievement of the end goal drives her — and often those for whom she is responsible.
Prima donnas, artists and conceptual designers exemplify the Perfectionist Archetype.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Regain a point of Willpower whenever you accomplish your goal without any demonstrable flaw or impediment.</field></object><object model="collector.archetype" pk="Rebel"><field name="source" type="CharField">VTM3</field><field name="description" type="TextField">The Rebel is a malcontent, never satisfied with the status quo or the system as it is. He hates authority and does everything in his power to challenge and undermine it. Perhaps the Rebel truly believes in his ideals, but it is just as likely that he bears authority figures some ill will over a misunderstanding or “wrong” done to him in the past. Teenagers, insurrectionists and
nonconformists all exemplify the Rebel Archetype.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Regain a point of Willpower whenever your actions adversely affect your chosen opposition. Rebels may oppose the government, the Church, a vampire prince, whatever. The player should choose whom or what his character rebels against when he adopts this Archetype.</field></object><object model="collector.archetype" pk="Rogue"><field name="source" type="CharField">VTM3</field><field name="description" type="TextField">Only one thing matters to the Rogue: herself. To each his own, and if others cannot protect their claims, they have no right to them. The Rogue is not necessarily a thug or bully, however.
She simply refuses to succumb to the whims of others. Rogues almost universally possess a sense of self-sufficiency. They have their own best interests in mind at all times. Prostitutes, capitalists and criminals all embody the Rogue Archetype.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Regain a point of Willpower when your self-centered disposition leads you to profit, materially or otherwise. At the Storyteller’s discretion, accumulating gain without exposing your
own weaknesses may let you regain two points of Willpower.</field></object><object model="collector.archetype" pk="Survivor"><field name="source" type="CharField">VTM3</field><field name="description" type="TextField">No matter what happens, no matter the odds or opposition, the Survivor always manages to pull through. Whether alone or with a group, the Survivor’s utter refusal to accept defeat often
makes the difference between success and failure. Survivors are frustrated by others’ acceptance of “what fate has in store” or willingness to withstand less than what they can achieve. Outcasts, street folk and idealists may well be Survivor Archetypes.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Regain one point of Willpower whenever you survive a threatening situation through tenacity, or when another persists in spite of opposition due to your counsel.</field></object><object model="collector.archetype" pk="Thrill-Seeker"><field name="source" type="CharField">VTM3</field><field name="description" type="TextField">The Thrill-Seeker lives for the rush brought on by danger. Unlike those of arguably saner disposition, the Thrill-Seeker actively pursues hazardous and possibly deadly situations. The Thrill-Seeker is not consciously suicidal or self-destructive — he simply seeks the stimulation of imminent disaster. Gangbangers, petty thieves and exhibitionists are all examples of the Thrill-Seeker Archetype.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Regain a point of Willpower any time you succeed at a dangerous task that you have deliberately undertaken. Thrill-Seekers are not stupid, however, and the Storyteller may choose not to reward a player who heedlessly sends her character into danger for the sole intent of harvesting Willpower.</field></object><object model="collector.archetype" pk="Traditionalist"><field name="source" type="CharField">VTM3</field><field name="description" type="TextField">The orthodox ways satisfy the Traditionalist, who prefers to accomplish her goals with time-tested methods. Why vary your course when what has worked in the past is good enough? The
Traditionalist finds the status quo acceptable, even preferable, to a change that might yield unpredictable results. Conservatives, judges and authority figures are all examples of Traditionalist Archetypes.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Regain a point of Willpower any time the proven ways turn out to be the best. Also, regain a point of Willpower any time you successfully resist change for its own sake.</field></object><object model="collector.archetype" pk="Trickster"><field name="source" type="CharField">VTM3</field><field name="description" type="TextField">The Trickster finds the absurd in everything. No matter how grim life (or unlife) may become, the Trickster always uncovers a kernel of humor within it. Tricksters cannot abide sorrow or
pain, and so they strive to lighten the spirits of those around them. Some Tricksters have even higher ideals, challenging static dogma by exposing its failures in humorous ways. Comedians,
satirists and social critics are examples of Trickster Archetypes.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Regain a point of Willpower any time you manage to lift others’ spirits, especially if you are able to deny your own pain in the process.</field></object><object model="collector.archetype" pk="Visionary"><field name="source" type="CharField">VTM3</field><field name="description" type="TextField">The Visionary is strong enough to look beyond the mundane and perceive the truly wondrous. Visionaries test accepted societal limits, and seek what few others have the courage to imagine. The Visionary rarely takes satisfaction in what society has to offer; she prefers to encourage society to offer what it could instead of what it does. Typically, society responds poorly to Visionaries, though it is they who are responsible for bringing about progress and change. Philosophers, inventors and the most inspired artists often have Visionary Archetypes.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Regain a point of Willpower each time you are able to convince others to have faith in your dreams and follow the course of action dictated by your vision.</field></object></django-objects>