<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<django-objects version="1.0"><object model="collector.rite" pk="Baptism of Fire"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">1</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Baptism of Fire (1)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">mystic</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">1</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField"></field><field name="description" type="TextField">Most tribes attempt to track down all children born to their Kinfolk within one month of the children's birth to see if they "share the blood." Those who are Garou are "baptized" in the light of their auspice moon, beside a rite fire. Such a baptism most commonly involves mingling ashes with a few drops of Garou blood; the mixture is then touched to the child's ears, nose, eyelids, and tongue. In the presence of one of the lesser tribal spirits, known as a Kin-Fetch, the babe is then held up to the moonlight while the baptizing Garou howls Gaia's greeting to the newborn. The ritemaster then has the Kin-Fetch kiss the infant. The spirit's fiery kiss inscribes a spiritual brand upon the babe in the form of the newborn's tribal pictograph. This mark is not visible on the newborn's body; the only mark left is spiritual. It is impossible to remove this spiritual brand. Such a mark can be traced and recognized by all Garou (including the Black Spiral Dancers, who all too often track down cubs of other tribes and capture them in order to create more of their foul number). The participating Kin-Fetch spirit is assigned to watch over the young Garou as she grows to maturity, so that the tribe may always know the child's location and whether she is endangered. When the child is about to undergo the First Change and is ready for the Rite of Passage, the spirit alerts the tribe. Unfortunately, minor spirits are notoriously weak-willed and easily distracted. All too often a Kin-Fetch loses track of its charge or becomes lost itself, leaving the young cub on her own. Such "lost cubs" often become Lunatics or recluses, terrified of themselves and unable to understand their powerful primal urges.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">The ritemaster makes a Cha+Rituals roll (difficulty 6). Only one success is required, but additional successes imrove the chance the kin-fetch will keep trakc of the child. This rite must be performed at nightunder the moon in which the child was born. Although this rite is normally performed within the month of the birth, the brand can be inscribed at any time before the cub reaches adolescence and undergoes her First Change.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Blood Walk"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">38</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Blood Walk (2)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">Thaumaturgy</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">2</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">kindred</field><field name="page" type="CharField"></field><field name="description" type="TextField">A thaumaturge casts this ritual on a blood sample from another vampire. Blood Walk is used to trace the subject’s Kindred lineage and the blood bonds in which the subject is involved.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">This ritual requires three hours to cast, reduced by 15 minutes for each success on the roll. It
requires one blood point from the subject. Each success allows the caster to “see back” one Generation (to a limit of the Fourth Generation — the Third Generation do not give up their secrets so easily), giving the caster both the true name of the ancestor and an image of his face. The caster also learns the Generation and Clan or bloodline from which the subject is descended.
With three successes, the caster also learns the identities of all parties with whom the subject shares a blood bond, either as regnant or thrall.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Bone Rhythms"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">2</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Bone Rhythms (0)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">minor</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">0</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField"></field><field name="description" type="TextField">This rite is performed in homage of the Garou's totem spirit. Each spirit has a different rhythm connected to it, and the Garou taps out this rhythm with special drumsticks to honor her totem. Such "sticks" are traditionally made of bone, but can be fashioned from any material.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Any garou who performs this rite three times per day for at least three consecutive days gains an additional die to any roll while in the spirit Realms. Once this die is used, the Garou must rebuild the energies for additional three days before regaining the extra die.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Breath of Gaia"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">3</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Breath of Gaia (0)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">minor</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">0</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField"></field><field name="description" type="TextField">During this rite the Garou breathes deeply of Gaia breath (air) 13 times. While so breathing, the Garou clears her mind of all things save her love of Gaia.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">The Garou must perform this rite at least once per day for one full cycle of the moon. So doing enables the Garou to lower by 2 the difficulty level of any one healing or detection roll.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Descent into the Underworld"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">42</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Descent into the Underworld (3)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">mystic</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">3</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField">213</field><field name="description" type="TextField">Most Garou think of the Umbra, the Gaian spirit world, as the only spirit realm that sits close to the physical world. Most Garou are wrong. The Underworld — the Land of the Dead, the Dark Umbra — sits astride the physical realm just as the Umbra does. Within it are trapped the ghosts of countless humans who died unable to let go of their lives and pass on into the cycle of souls, as Gaia intended. The Underworld is a bleak landscape mirroring all that is decayed or departed in the living world, as the Penumbra is a reflection expressing the world’s spiritual nature. Terrible, unstable portals lead deeper yet into the Underworld, a land of spirit-storms and nightmare mazes where few Garou have ever ventured and from which fewer still have ever returned. This rite is primarily known and used by the Silent Striders, but a few other tribes and camps make use of it as well (most notably the Black Furies and Uktena).</field><field name="system" type="TextField">This rite takes five minutes to perform. The ritemaster must sacrifice a living mammal and touch every character to be affected by the rite with at least a fingerprint of its blood. He then draws sigils on the ground nearby with the remaining blood. The player should roll Intelligence + Occult (difficulty equals the local Gauntlet). Success on this roll takes the ritemaster to the Underworld; each additional success takes one of the other characters marked (if there aren’t enough successes to go around, those with the highest Gnosis are transported first).</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Enchant the Forest"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">40</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Enchant the Forest (4)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">accord</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">4</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField">205</field><field name="description" type="TextField">Everyone’s heard of enchanted forests in which the trees themselves seem aware, strange voices whisper, wicked witches roam, and goblins and fae of all manner plague the weary traveler. Though the Garou used to rule the wilds, humanity encroaches more and more on their ranges. Hundreds of years ago, Theurges developed a rite with which to frustrate such expansion. This rite, Enchant the Forest, awakens the spirits of the land and urges them to protect the Wyld. These spirits awaken and move to resist any human settlements in the area.
Springs dry out. The winter grows harsher than ever before, yet the trees are remarkably fast-growing and resilient. Food decays and rots in no time, and vermin and insects infest the area. Attempts to construct power lines fail inexplicably. On the rare occasions when cell phones are able to get any reception at all, their calls are interrupted by threatening screeches of static and disturbing whispers. Humans eventually either leave or die, and the wilderness reclaims its lost property. The area seems haunted for years afterwards. The trees are dark and threatening, and strange sounds emanate from the woods at night. The spirits, once roused, don’t rest again for a very long time. Superstitious tales of haunted lands circulate, and many humans give the area wide berth. Unfortunately, many others may become interested — government agencies, paranormal investigators, and other supernatural beings. The ritemaster must take a twig from a tree never seen by human eyes, make a container from the belly of an animal never hunted by humans, and fill the pouch with water from a pond never touched by mankind. He then stirs the water, pours it close to the borders of the wild woods, and calls on the spirits of nature to awaken and defend themselves. He sends messengers to the north, south, east and west, to call to the spirits there. The ritemaster must sing to the spirits for three days.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Standard roll. The immediate effects of this rite last for a full year, if they are not disrupted by some sort of supernatural intervention. The area so charmed cannot exceed the farthest distance the messengers have traveled by foot in the three days. If a caern is located within five miles (8 km) of the ritual location, the difficulty is reduced by one.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Gaia's Vengeful Teeth"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">4</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Gaia's Vengeful Teeth (5)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">punishment</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">5</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField">216</field><field name="description" type="TextField">As one of the greatest punishments among the Garou, this rite is reserved for traitors, those who consort with the Wyrm or cowards whose actions (or  lack thereof) cause the deaths of many others. At least five werewolves drag the traitor to a spot of hard, cracked earth and stones. The ritemaster then stabs a sharpened twig or stone into her own hand as she recites the traitor’s sins against Gaia. Smearing her blood over the traitor’s eyes, ears and forehead, the ritemaster cries in grief and rage. As the blood and tears drip to the hard ground, the rite takes effect. From that moment on, whatever of Gaia touches the traitor transforms into razor-sharp silver so long as it touches his flesh. Crinos hunters then chase the traitor like a dog. The ground beneath the traitor chews into his feet, and his death becomes an agonizing ordeal. The offender’s name is then stricken from all histories, and it will be spoken only as a curse from that moment forward.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">As long as the ritemaster’s blood touches the traitor’s body, the traitor cannot step sideways into the Umbra. No one survives being subject to this rite.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Gathering of the Departed"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">5</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Gathering of the Departed (1)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">death</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">1</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField"></field><field name="description" type="TextField">This rite is enacted in honor of the newly dead. A Galliard or a packmate of the departed werewolf usually performs the rite. The specifics of the rite vary dramatically from tribe to tribe. For example, a Fianna ritemaster leads the sept in the telling of tales, both raucous and heroic, about the fallen Garou. In contrast stands the Wendigo’s solemn rite in which the ritemaster and all the fallen one’s packmates stand on the highest peak available, tails to the wind, and howl out their pride and grief to speed their companion onward to her next life. The exact form of the rite is less important than the acknowledgment it represents.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">The ritemaster leads the release of the Garou’s combined emotions into the spirit world. At the Storyteller’s discretion, this rite may make the deceased’s spirit easier to contact through the Ancestors Background.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Greet the Moon"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">6</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Greet the Moon (0)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">Minor Rite</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">0</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField"></field><field name="description" type="TextField">This rite is an exuberant paean to Luna. During this rite, the Garou howls an elaborate greeting to the moon. This greeting varies with the phase of the moon.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Performing this rite each night at moonrise for a full phase of the moon enables the Garou to add one die to all social interactions with Garou of that phase's auspice the next time the moon reaches the phase in question.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Greet the Sun"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">7</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Greet the Sun (0)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">Minor Rite</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">0</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField"></field><field name="description" type="TextField">Certain Children of Gaia and a few Uktena and Wendigo practice this rite. It's similar to Green the Moon but is performed at sunrise.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">The Garou must sing Helios' praises for nine consecutive days. If the Garou does so, Helios grants his devotee an additional die when attempting to sense Wyrm creatures or Wyrm-taint, provided the Garou continues to sing his praises daily. If the Garou misses even one day, he must begin this rite anew to reap its benefits.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Hunting Prayer"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">8</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Hunting Prayer (0)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">Minor Rite</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">0</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField"></field><field name="description" type="TextField">This common rite takes many forms, but it always involves pausing before the start of a hunt to praise Gaia and all her creatures. In addition, the Garou chooses some item to hold her prayers. This item can range from an old belt to a tooth, but the werewolf must have it with her when she hunts. If she loses the item, she must choose another item and start her prayers anew.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">If a Garou performs this rite before every hunt for three turnings of the moon, she receives an additional die to all tracking rolls so long as she continues her pre-hunt prayers. If she hunts even once without praying, she must renew her prayers for another three months before again receiving the bonus.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Incantation of the Shepherd"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">39</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Incantation of the Shepherd (1)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">Thaumaturgy</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">1</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">kindred</field><field name="page" type="CharField"></field><field name="description" type="TextField">This ritual enables the caster to mystically locate all members of his herd. While intoning the ritual’s vocal component, he spins in a slow circle with a glass object of some sort held to each of his eyes. At the end of the ritual, he has a subliminal sense of the direction and distance to each of his regular vessels.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">System: This ritual gives the character the location (relative to him) of every member of his Herd. If he does not have the Herd Background, Incantation of the Shepherd locates the closest three mortals from whom the caster has fed at least three times each. This ritual has a maximum range of 10 miles or 15 kilometers times the character’s Herd Background, or five miles (eight kilometers) if he has no points in that Background.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Last Blessing"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">57</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Last Blessing (3)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">death</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">3</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField">209</field><field name="description" type="TextField">The mere existence of metis threatens the Veil, as they are born and die in Crinos form. This blessing is given to a dying or just-deceased metis by the ritemaster. It ensures that the corpse will assume the natural form which the metis most preferred — human or wolf — arousing no suspicion. Many metis have received this rite with joy, seeing it as a sign of Gaia’s forgiveness.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Standard roll. The ritemaster lays hands on the metis and chants the Song of the True Form, then spends one Gnosis point. The metis’s body changes to Homid or Lupus form, and the change is permanent. This rite must be performed within an hour of death, and has no effect on a live metis.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Mirror of Second Sight"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">37</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Mirror of Second Sight (3)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">Thaumaturgy</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">3</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">kindred</field><field name="page" type="CharField"></field><field name="description" type="TextField">This object is an oval mirror no less than four inches (10 cm) wide and no more than 18 inches (45 cm) in length. It looks like a normal mirror, but once created, the vampire can use it to see the supernatural: It reflects the true form of Lupines and faeries, and enables the owner to see ghosts as they move though the Underworld. The caster creates the mirror by bathing an ordinary mirror in a quantity of her own blood while reciting a ritual incantation.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">System: The ritual requires one point of the vampire’s blood. Thereafter, the mirror reflects images of other supernatural creatures’ true forms — werewolves appear in their hulking man-wolf shapes, magi glow in a scintillating nimbus, ghosts become visible (in the mirror), and so on. Sometimes, the mirror also reveals those possessed of True Faith in clouds of golden light.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Moot Rite"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">9</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Moot Rite (1)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">caern</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">1</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField"></field><field name="description" type="TextField">A moot cannot open until this rite is completed, recharging the caern with Gnosis. The rite always includes a prolonged howl led by a werewolf known as the Master of the Howl. This howl varies by tribe and sept, but always expresses the unique nature of the sept. All werewolves present must form a circle within the caern itself before they commence howling. Numerous variations on the basic requirements exist: The Red Talons often bite their paws and scratch blood into the earth, while Uktena pass their most powerful fetish from one to another as each in turn adds her voice to the howl. However it is done, the howl must echo forth and the eternal circle must form.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Max Gnosis (diff 7)  The rite must be performed at least once per month to keep the caern consecrated. During the course of a moot, the participants must empower the caern with a combined total of five Gnosis points per caern level in order to replenish it fully.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Prayer for the Prey"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">10</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Prayer for the Prey (0)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">Minor Rite</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">0</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField"></field><field name="description" type="TextField">A specific form of the Rite of Contrition, this rite involves the werewolf stepping sideways into the Umbra just after making a kill, subsequently thanking the spirit of the prey for giving its own life that the Garou might survive. Performing this rite is a sign of respect to Gaia, her children, and life itself.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">The character must perform this rite upon every beast of Gaia (not including Wyrm-spawn) he slays for one full turning of the moon. Should this be done, all of her difficulty numbers drop by one when dealing with Nature-spirits. This bonus lasts until she kills without taking time to thank the creature's spirit.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of Accomplishment"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">11</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of Accomplishment (2)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">renown</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">2</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField">217</field><field name="description" type="TextField">This rite is used to honor a werewolf and recognize the trials he has endured to attain his current standing. An elder will call the honored Garou forward, much as the Garou might be called forward should the elders want to punish or criticize her. As the Garou advances, the elder begins listing all of the things the Garou did to gain the acclaim. The Rite of Accomplishment then takes place, and anyone who wishes to speak on behalf of the Garou being honored may do so. In conclusion, the elder says something along the lines of, “She is made greater in her tribe, her sept and greater among the People everywhere. Let this be known.”</field><field name="system" type="TextField">This rite is performed when a character has 10 points of temporary Renown in a category and wishes to gain a point of permanent Renown. The difficulty is only 4 unless someone disputes the rite. (In such an instance, the difficulty rises to 6). Only one success is required. A failure on the roll is considered indicative of a failing in the applicant. The ritemaster often receives a portent from Gaia showing the unworthiness of the applicant. If the roll botches, the applicant must undergo a penance before anyone will again give him the Rite of Accomplishment. Such is the injustice of Garou society.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of Becoming"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">12</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of Becoming (2)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">mystic</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">2</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField">212</field><field name="description" type="TextField">Werewolves must perform this rite at an Anchorhead Domain. Once completed, it enables them to travel into the Deep Umbra. The most common version of this rite requires the Garou to make a braid from three of her hairs, three pieces of fine copper wire, and three tendrils of ivy or other vine. Lengths of silk thread are sometimes substituted for the hair or wire. When the braid has been constructed, the Garou ties it around his own wrist and howls three words of power.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">If the braid is destroyed while the Garou is in the Deep Umbra, the werewolf takes one level of aggravated damage and risks becoming lost forever if she doesn’t return quickly to the Near Umbra.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of Binding"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">13</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of Binding (1)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">mystic</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">1</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField">210</field><field name="description" type="TextField">This rite binds a spirit to a werewolf, making it his servant. The more powerful the spirit is, the more difficult the process is. Although any encountered spirit is subject to binding, the Garou generally feel that spirits should be bound only when needed. Binding spirits for excessive lengths of time is generally viewed as callous abuse of those who should be the allies of the Garou. This point doesn’t go uncontested, however, particularly by the mystics of the Uktena tribe. Spirits trapped through this rite may be bound into temporary service or into objects to create talens (see p. 227). No spirit allows itself to be bound unless it is friendly to the binding character’s totem. Spirits can be bound into objects, places, and people, although the Garou generally don’t perform the last feat unless the need is great. Failing this rite can be dangerous, for the spirit is very likely to become hostile and attempt to harm the mystic.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">A Garou can attempt this rite only in the presence of a spirit, and it is usually performed in the Umbra. When attempting to bind a spirit, a Garou must first spend a number of Gnosis points (minimum of one). Each point of Gnosis spent reduces the spirit’s Gnosis rating by one. The Garou’s player must then roll Willpower (difficulty equals the spirit’s adjusted Gnosis). The number of successes indicates how long the spirit may be forced into service, with each success binding the spirit for one week. In the case of a talen, the spirit is bound until the object is used.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of Boasting"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">54</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of Boasting (1)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">renown</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">1</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField">216</field><field name="description" type="TextField">Boasting and bragging have always been a vital aspect of warrior cultures. Boasts serve to work up a fighter’s courage while putting fear into the opponent. But to truly impress, the boaster must back up his claims. This rite is more than formalized bragging, for it forces the Garou to “put up or shut up.” Before a battle or mission, the Garou boasts before all assembled that he will perform a particularly impressive feat (for example, “I will kill three Black Spirals with only my claws,” “I will
scale the electrified razorwire of the refinery” or “I will be the first to reach the shield wall, there to wrest the enemy’s standard from his dead hand.”). The boast is performed in a ritual fashion, with a short recitation of lineage and a summary of glorious deeds performed to date. If he makes good on his boast, he magnifies the Glory of the act. If he fails, the resulting derision of his
peers costs him Glory; boasting is only respected if you can back it up. This rite is most commonly used among the Fianna, Get of Fenris, and Wendigo, but most tribes have some version of it.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Standard roll, though the difficulty may be modified by the difficulty and glory of the proposed feat — modest goals are harder to boast about than impressive lunacy. For every two successes, the boast earns a potential extra temporary Glory, up to the amount of Glory the feat would ordinarily garner. If the boast is carried through, the Garou earns the Glory bonus. If he fails and lives, he loses that amount. If he dies while carrying out his deed, there is neither loss nor gain of extra Renown. A single pack may boast of a deed, but only the pack leader can perform the rite. In this case, the difficulty is increased by one, and the entire pack gains or loses the Glory award.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of Caern Building"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">14</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of Caern Building (5)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">caern</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">5</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField">208</field><field name="description" type="TextField">This powerful rite creates a new caern by drawing the spirit world and the physical world closer together. Simply reciting the rite draws the attention  of the Wyrm’s servants, and actually performing the rite has been known to prove fatal. Only the most powerful and wise mystics dare lead such an undertaking.
A powerful Theurge is almost always selected to perform this most sacred of rites. Many Garou must channel their energy through a powerful leader to have even a hope of success. Whole packs have been known to die in the agony of failed attempts.
Once the physical focus for the heart of the caern is chosen, the area must be cleansed of all taints in preparation for its transformation. All Garou participating in the rite must undergo a Rite of Cleansing, at minimum. The ritemaster performs a series of minor rituals, meditations, and other physical preliminaries to prepare for her awesome task. The sept must post sentries, for servants of the Wyrm almost invariably attempt to disrupt such a great rite. Only the mightiest warriors are chosen for such an assignment, and their protection is critical to the success of the rite. The leader of the rite is helpless while he chants a long litany of verses designed to draw a great spirit into the prepared caern. Although it is possible to create a specific type of caern, most leaders leave this choice to Gaia and accept whatever caern she grants the sept. 
The rite must be performed between the hours of sunset and sunrise during the waxing of the moon. Only the Black Spiral Dancers create caerns during the moon’s waning.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">The rite lasts from dusk until dawn. As the sun breaks over the horizon, the ritemaster makes a Wits + Rituals roll at difficulty 8 (modified downward by one for every five Garou participating in the rite and spending Gnosis over and above the 13 necessary participants, to a minimum of difficulty 4). The number of successes gained determines the level of the resulting caern:
Successes
1–3 = Level One
4–6 = Level Two
7–8 = Level Three
9+ = Level Four
Because an enormous amount of Gnosis is needed to break through the Gauntlet and empower the new caern, a minimum of 13 Garou, one for each moon of the year, must participate in the rite. At the end of the rite, the participating Garou channel Gnosis into the nascent caern — a total of 100 points of Gnosis is necessary to awaken the sacred site. If an insufficient amount of Gnosis is offered, the rite’s participants begin to suffer aggravated wounds as their life-force is sacrificed to create the caern. Each wound counts as three more Gnosis points toward the total. The complete the ritual, each of the 13 core participants must sacrifice a dot of permanent Gnosis. Such is the damaged state of the world that the Rite of Caern Building can no longer naturally awaken a level five caern — only an additional offering of Gnosis can bring that sort of purity and power back to the dying earth. Offering an additional 100 points of Gnosis — 200 Gnosis in total — empowers the rite, creating a caern one level higher than the ritemaster’s successes would otherwise indicate. The dangers of the rite are many. Failure scours the bodies and spirits of all Garou involved in the rite, both those donating Gnosis and those protecting them, inflicting four levels of lethal damage from spiritual backlash. A botch inflicts seven levels of lethal damage; those driven below Incapacitated by this damage suffer severe Battle Scars (see p. 259). Minions of the Wyrm ultimately pose the greatest threat to the rite. As soon as it begins, all Wyrm-corrupted beings (Banes, fomori, Black Spiral Dancers, even particularly degenerate vampires or depraved ghosts) for miles around become aware of the rite; many will stop at nothing to prevent its completion. The Garou can expect a siege lasting at least until dawn, and likely longer. If a player’s character should somehow assume the role of ritemaster and succeed, she receives three points of Glory Renown, five points of Honor Renown, and seven points of Wisdom Renown. Anyone else participating in the rite receives five points of Glory Renown and three points of Honor Renown. This task is a legendary one that deserves a suitable reward.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of Cleansing"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">15</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of Cleansing (1)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">accord</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">1</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField"></field><field name="description" type="TextField">This rite purifies a person, place or object, allowing it to be used without fear of contamination by the Wyrm. To perform this rite the Garou must inscribe a circle on the earth, walking widdershins (counterclockwise) around the afflicted person(s) or object(s) while holding a smoldering branch or torch. She must use a branch (preferably willow or birch) dipped in pure water or snow to asperge the object or person cleansed. As this is done, all Garou present release an eerie, otherworldly howl in an attempt to "frighten away" and this banish the corrupting influence. Ideally, this rite is performed at dawn, but it can be performed at any time.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">This rite can be cast upon more than one person or object, but the leader must spend one Gnosis point on each extra thing or person in need of cleansing. The difficulty level equals the Gnosis of the spirit that inflicetedthe contagion (maximum difficulty 10). Only one success is required. If the rite is performed at dawn, the difficulty level of the rite is reduced by one. Note that this rite cannot heal wounds or damage caused by contamination. It only removes any existing contamination. [Cha+Rituals]</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of Contrition"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">16</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of Contrition (1)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">accord</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">1</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField"></field><field name="description" type="TextField">This rite is a form of apology used to prevent the enmity of spirits or Garou whom an individual has annoyed, or to prevent war between septs or tribes. The rite most often involves the enactor dropping to her belly and sliding forward. The ritemaster may also whine and lick his paws or hands. If performed well, however, a simple inclination of the head may suffice. To enact this rite successfully, the Garou must either give a small gift to the offended individual or, in the case of a spirit, possess some aspect of the spirit in question (for example, a clay falcon if the Garou is appealing to the totem spirit Falcon).</field><field name="system" type="TextField">The difficulty level of the rite equals the Rage of the target spirit or werewolf. A single success suffices for a gracious apology, but may not be enough to mend friendships or forgive grievous errors. The more successes, the greater the wrong that can be forgiven. Werewolves who refuse to recognize a Rite of Contrition are looked upon badly by elders. Most spirits will always accept a well-performed rite. This effect lasts until the Garou performs another action that could harm or insult the other.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of Growth"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">46</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of Growth (1)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">mystic</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">1</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField">210</field><field name="description" type="TextField">This favorite of urban Garou, particularly Glass Walkers, allows plants to grow in strange locations. The plants don’t grow unusually quickly, but can grow in plastic, concrete, or other unusual places, drawing nutrients from the source. Three Garou are needed to make this rite work. The ritemaster makes an indentation in the surface using a claw, and plants the seed of the plant into it. The three then hold hands in a triangle around it, kneeling, and request the spirit of the material that it nurture and care for the plant. If the spirit agrees, a small green shoot will appear immediately.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">The ritemaster rolls Wits + Rituals. The difficulty depends on the surface and area. An abandoned lot is 5, a typical city building is 7, and an oil spill would be 9. Each success guarantees the plant’s survival for one month. After that, as much regular watering and care as for any other plant is required.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of Heritage"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">47</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of Heritage (1)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">mystic</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">1</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField">211</field><field name="description" type="TextField">Galliards and Philodox alike favor this genealogical rite, albeit for slightly different reasons. Some Garou use it to verify the identity of a hero’s descendants before passing on an inheritance; others use it to identify the father of a metis cub if none is forthcoming. The ritemaster draws the blood of the subject with a silver knife and sings a long paean to the ancestor-spirits of his tribe and any others that might be watching over the subject. As he completes the song, the ancestor-spirits whisper the subject’s heritage into his ears.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Standard roll. Success reveals the subject’s true heritage for one generation back per success (for example, two successes would reveal the subject’s heritage as far back as his grandparents). In addition, the ritemaster receives the answer to one specific question about the subject’s heritage per success; e.g., “What was this cub’s paternal grandfather’s profession?” or “Does the blood of any other tribe run in this cub’s veins?” The answer will be accurate, as long as the answer can be found within the number of generations revealed; if the ritemaster gained four successes, for example, he could not ask “Is this child descended from Frode,” but he could accurately tell if the child’s great-great-grandfather claimed descent from Frode or not. The Rite of Heritage works just as well with humans or wolves (although wolves, lacking names, are harder to accurately identify), even non-Kin or mages. It does not, however, work on the undead or on fae.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of Keres"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">17</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of Keres (4)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">seasonal</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">4</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField"></field><field name="description" type="TextField"></field><field name="system" type="TextField"></field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of Ostracism"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">18</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of Ostracism (2)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">punishment</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">2</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField">214</field><field name="description" type="TextField">This rite is a fairly common punishment for lesser crimes, yet its effects can be devastating during wartime. This rite estranges the punished Garou from her tribe, sept, and sometimes even her pack. The tribe will thereafter treat the individual as a nonentity. She is ignored as much as possible and forced to fend for herself for even basic needs, although no hostile actions are taken against the non-wolf (in theory at least, although some Garou have been known to injure ostracized werewolves “accidentally”). In a life-or-death situation, the tribe (friends and packmates in particular) might aid the offender, but even then only grudgingly. Otherwise, the punished Garou is ignored utterly. Garou present at this rite form a circle around the chastised werewolf (if present), and each participant calls out once to Gaia, then to her brethren the name of the offender, followed by the words: “Of all Gaia’s children, I have no such brother/sister.” The speaker then turns counterclockwise to face away from the circle. Once all present have spoken, they drift away into the night.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">This punishment normally lasts from one phase of the moon to the next. It can, however, last as long as the sept or tribe leaders desire. For serious crimes, the punishment may even be decreed permanent, essentially exiling the offender from her sept or tribe. The ostracized Garou loses one point of Glory Renown, five points of Honor Renown, and one point of Wisdom Renown.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of Passage"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">19</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of Passage (2)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">renown</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">2</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField">217</field><field name="description" type="TextField">After a cub undergoes his First Change and becomes aware that he is a werewolf, he must undergo his Rite of Passage. Werewolves are not accorded adulthood or respect until they pass this seminal rite; they are mere cubs until that time. They are not even considered true Garou, and Shadow Lords do not refer to them as such until this rite is completed. Similarly, a cub is not a member of any tribe until his Rite of Passage. A male cub born to the Black Furies, for example, becomes a member of whatever tribe will offer him a place among them by use of this rite. During a Rite of Passage, the cubs must complete a dangerous quest meant to prove that they have the courage, honor, and wisdom befitting a werewolf. However, few cubs undergo this rite alone. They are often joined by their pack-to-be, other cubs who are also coming of age. The ritemaster commands the would-be pack to go out into the world with a definite goal to achieve, and he forbids it to return until it has tried its best to accomplish this goal. Different tribes impose different goals, although multi-tribal septs usually reach a compromise. A Wendigo rite often takes the form of a vision quest, while the Get of Fenris commonly send their cubs into combat with Wyrm-spawn. Invisible spirits sometimes accompany the cubs in order to watch over them and report their doings to the elders. If the cubs succeed in their quest, a ritemaster performs this rite upon them, marking them with a pictogram that brands them as full-fledged Garou. These pictograms are usually painted, but the Red Talons carve them into the flesh of the young heroes. If the cubs fail, however, they are considered second-class citizens until they are granted another opportunity to prove themselves.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Before the Rite of Passage, Garou are not yet Rank 1.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of Praise"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">55</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of Praise (2)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">renown</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">2</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField">217</field><field name="description" type="TextField">This rite honors a werewolf who has given more, risked more, and sacrificed more than necessary for the good of other Garou, Gaia, or anything related. The entire sept is gathered as the ritemaster presents the commendation, often with a token worthy of the honoree, such as a fetish, as a final reward. This rite is not used lightly, or to reward expected behavior — it honors only the greatest.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">The ritemaster presents to the sept the deeds and actions of the chosen Garou warranting such praise. For each success on a Charisma + Rituals roll (difficulty 6), the praised Garou gains an extra die to use for Social dice pools within the sept over the next three months.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of Reawakening"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">20</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of Reawakening (2)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">seasonal</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">2</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField">218</field><field name="description" type="TextField">This rite celebrates the vernal equinox, the time of rebirth. The ritemaster begins the rite at sundown by leading the gathered Garou on a quest into the Umbra. Such a quest is sometimes symbolic, but more and more often as the time of the Apocalypse draws near, the questors seek true danger in the Umbral Realms — or it finds them on its own. The quest always involves seven trials. These trials represent the seven gates that bar the way to the Underworld. Such trials vary dramatically from tribe to tribe, but there are always a variety of challenges presented to the members. One test might involve facing a Bane in combat, while another challenge might consist of finding a fetish lost within the Deep Umbra. Each test requires the participants to relinquish something of themselves, be it a cherished personal fetish, an old grudge or false pride. If the Garou can win their way past these challenge gates, they can renew the Earth, banishing the winter-spirits and paving the way for the green, growing season. At the end of the rite, the werewolves return to their bodies. At this time many tribes seek out Garou Kinfolk, or other humans and wolves, and reacquaint themselves with the joys of the flesh, celebrating the incredible beauty of life and the necessity of its continuation in future generations. Not surprisingly, this is the night when a large percentage of metis cubs are conceived. Although such couplings are always taboo, the intense drama of the rite sometimes overrides such concerns.</field><field name="system" type="TextField"></field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of Renunciation"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">21</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of Renunciation (2)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">accord</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">2</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField"></field><field name="description" type="TextField">In this rare rite, a Garou rejects the auspice under which he was born and chooses a new auspice. The rite must be performed during the phase of the moon the Garou wishes to embrace. Water from a silver basin exposed to Luna's radiance is poured over the naked Garou, washing him clean of all he once was, including all Rank. He is now free to start anew as a member of his adopted auspice. Well, almost free - many Garou view such a "Shifting Moon" with suspicion. The Shadow Lords and Silver Fangs in particular see this rite as a grave insult to Luna and are loathe to trust those Garou who cannot bear the weight of their assigned burdens.</field><field name="system" type="TextField"></field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of Spirit Awakening"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">49</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of Spirit Awakening (2)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">mystic</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">2</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField">212</field><field name="description" type="TextField">This rite is used to awaken a sleeping (inactive) spirit. To perform this rite, a Garou must play a rhythm on some form of instrument (drums are the most common). While the Garou plays, any other participating werewolves pace around the ritemaster, howling and growling in counter-point to the beat. When performed on a mundane item, this rite enlivens the object’s spirit, causing it to awaken and appear in the Umbra. For example, if the rite is performed on a VW bus, any Garou stepping sideways could see the bus as a true part of the landscape. However, it would appear as a stationary object in the Penumbra unless someone on the physical plane began to drive it, in which case it would appear as a driverless vehicle to anyone in the Umbra. When performed on plants, this rite is known as sanctification. Plant-spirits are generally benevolent, and an awakened plant spirit will lend its powers as though it were a talen (one use). Different plants grant different abilities when sanctified. For example, sanctified foxglove protects against faerie magic (adding two to the difficulty of any faerie spell).</field><field name="system" type="TextField">The ritemaster must play a musical instrument or sing a song (talent doesn’t matter). The difficulty of the roll is the spirit’s Rage. Failure means that the spirit remains dormant. The Storyteller must decide whether the spirit is hostile or friendly to its awakener. Awakening a spirit doesn’t allow any control over it. Commanding an awakened spirit requires either a Rite of Binding or a Gift. This rite doesn’t work on sentient beings such as humans. Such individuals are already as “awakened” as they’re going to get.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of Summoning"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">50</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of Summoning (2)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">mystic</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">2</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField">212</field><field name="description" type="TextField">Garou mystics are adept at calling spirits, be they minor Gafflings, totem spirits, or even Incarna. Summoning spirits involves complex rituals, long periods of meditation, and tribal mantra chanting. Within the Umbra, this process is far easier. This rite compels spirits to seek those who call them. Furthermore, the spirit cannot escape its caller once the summoning is completed successfully, and it must attend the mystic. Many spirits, particularly minor ones, are too weak to resist a powerful summoning. Powerful ones come out of curiosity. The chance of a successful  summoning depends upon the skill of the mystic, the power of the spirit, and the strength of the area’s Gauntlet.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">The ritemaster must pierce the Gauntlet just as if he were entering the Umbra (Gnosis roll against the local Gauntlet level). A mystic already within the Umbra is not required to pierce the Gauntlet. The power level of the spirit determines the difficulty level of a successful summoning. The storyteller should feel free to adjust the previous tables as she wishes, particularly as appropriate to totems. In certain cases, a Garou who attempts to summon a specific spirit will have no chance of success. At other times, he will have almost no chance of failure. The Storyteller is advised to treat each use of this rite individually and to use common sense in her decisions. A Garou who summons an Incarna or Celestine avatar successfully gains two points of Wisdom Renown, unless the summons is done frivolously.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of Talisman Dedication"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">22</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of Talisman Dedication (1)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">mystic</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">1</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField"></field><field name="description" type="TextField">This common rite allows a werewolf to bind objects to her body, allowing them to fit her various forms (jeans will grow to accommodate the Crinos form rather than splitting at the seams, for example) and accompany the Garou into the Umbra. Such talismans are most commonly mundane items, for spiritual items such as fetishes and talens remain with the werewolf in all forms and in the Umbra automatically. A werewolf most often performs this rite during the phase of the moon under which she was born. Each auspice has its own peculiar ritual.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">The cost is one Gnosis point per object dedicated, and a character may never have more objects bound to himself than his Gnosis score. Conceptually linked groups of objects may count as a single object as the Storyteller’s discretion. For example, as a set of clothing would be considered one object rather than one shirt, one pair of pants, two socks, and so on; or a box of ammunition might be dedicated to the character, rather than requiring one dedication per bullet.
Objects will generally resize themselves to accommodate the character’s various forms (such as a backpack’s straps lengthening to accommodate Crinos form), but may simply meld with the character in forms where they can be of no use — for example, a knife may become a knife-shaped tattoo in Hispo. Others must spend a point of Willpower to attempt to steal dedicated objects from the werewolf. [Wits+Rituals]</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of Wounding"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">31</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of Wounding (1)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">renown</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">1</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField">217</field><field name="description" type="TextField">This rite celebrates a Garou’s first battle wound. Each tribe marks this moment differently, but all honor this sign of courage. Many tribes rub ash into at least part of the wound to form a scar of remembrance. The Get of Fenris always end this rite with a fierce all-night revel filled with drinking and fighting. By contrast, the Children of Gaia end their Rites of Wounding with prayers for peace and understanding among all creatures.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Only the wounded character and the ritemaster must be present for this rite, although the werewolf’s pack and sept are normally present. The wounded character receives two points of Glory if this rite succeeds.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of the Cardboard Palace"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">48</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of the Cardboard Palace (1)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">mystic</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">1</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField">211</field><field name="description" type="TextField">A Bone Gnawer favorite, this rite allows the Garou to transform any flimsy structure into a decent place to sleep. This often involves a lot of cardboard and newspaper, but this rite can be invoked just about anywhere a werewolf needs to call home for the night — a few torndown branches arranged into a messy lean-to in the woods functions as well as a pile of converted trash in an alley. The “walls” of the dwelling become water-resistant and insulated, keeping everyone inside warm and dry. The rite can even be performed in full view of humans without breaking the Veil. For powerful Theurges, the cardboard palace is even a place of healing, as well.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">The ritemaster’s player rolls Intelligence + Survival (difficulty 6). One success is all that’s needed to create a comfortable place to sleep. If a point of Gnosis is spent before making the roll, the shelter is more than just comfortable — the Garou (and any other Fera) living inside the cardboard palace can roll Stamina after a full day of rest within; three successes heals one aggravated health level. A cardboard palace lasts for one full day per success on the activation roll.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of the Fetish"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">23</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of the Fetish (3)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">mystic</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">3</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField">213</field><field name="description" type="TextField">This rite allows a werewolf to create a fetish (an object with a spirit bound into it). To do so, the Garou must first cleanse the potential fetish by placing it under running water (sufficiently drinkable flowing tap water counts), burying it in pure earth, exposing the object to constant breezes, or suspending it above flame for three consecutive nights. The Garou must then force or persuade a spirit to enter the prepared object. The Fianna claim that cajoling or flattering a spirit produces the best results, while the Bone Gnawers and Silent Striders claim that bribery (expending Gnosis) works best.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">The ritemaster rolls Wits + Rituals (difficulty 10). Each point of permanent Gnosis that the character spends during the rite reduces the difficulty by two. The difficulty can also be lowered by roleplaying, if the ritemaster does a good job persuading the spirit to enter the fetish (by providing chiminage, undergoing a quest to prove her sincerity or worthiness, flattery, etc). If the Garou attempts to force a spirit into the fetish, she must first attack the spirit and reduce it to zero Essence before attempting to bind it into the fetish.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of the Glorious Past"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">44</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of the Glorious Past (3)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">caern</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">3</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField">206</field><field name="description" type="TextField">A caern has its own history and heritage, regardless of the Garou that currently inhabit it. Learning the history of a caern is a fascinating undertaking that can take years. However, this rite allows the Garou to experience the nuances of the caern’s development as a fever dream, causing those years to seem to pass in a few short moments. To enact this rite, the ritemaster must draw up a map of the caern as it was when it was first founded (which may require some research). This map is then burnt at the center of the caern. As the map burns, all Garou present growl quietly as the ritemaster recites the history of the caern. All werewolves present see the caern’s formation and any other important details in its history as though in a dream.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">The player rolls Intelligence + Rituals (difficulty 9 minus the ritemaster’s Ancestors rating). If performed successfully, each participant receives an additional dot of Ancestors until the next dawn; this occurs even if the character is normally incapable of possessing this Background (as the ancestors thus contacted are former guardians of the caern rather than a given character’s personal forebears).This ritual also “primes” the caern; the next caern rite performed therein receives a –1 difficulty.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of the Jackdaw"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">51</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of the Jackdaw (1)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">punishment</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">1</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField">214</field><field name="description" type="TextField">The Rite of the Jackdaw is used to punish those Garou who have broken a promise of secrecy. It causes the subject to uncontrollably tell everyone he meets about the most private and trivial matters of his life. This ritual won’t cause the subject to reveal other secrets he’s been sworn to keep — and cannot force him to break the Litany by revealing his nature to humans — but it will almost certainly cause him to reveal personal information that embarrasses only him. This rite can be rather humiliating, and many Garou who are subject to it find themselves overcome by Rage at their embarrassment. It is considered the height of dishonor to take retribution against a Garou who has used this ritual in a just fashion. Subjects who wish to avoid the rite’s effects simply abandon all contact with others for a few days, which is considered to be an acceptable response.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">This rite takes ten minutes to perform. The ritemaster symbolically carves a number of open-mouth sigils into bits of wood and distributes them ritualistically around the subject of the rite (who must remain more or less still during the rite, though he doesn’t necessarily have to be willing). The ritemaster rolls Manipulation + Subterfuge (difficulty 7). For each success, the target suffers from the effects described above for one day. The target can expend Willpower to avoid stating some particularly odious personal secret.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of the Loyal Pack"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">43</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of the Loyal Pack (3)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">accord</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">3</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField">205</field><field name="description" type="TextField">A leader needs respect from those that follow him if he (and they) wish to succeed. Usually, only packs that have been working together for some time and who trust each other enough to further cement those bonds perform this rite.
The rite makes the whole pack’s focus and commitment dependent on the pack alpha. In effect, they submit completely to him, in the hope of gaining an advantage from his commitment to working for the benefit of all. Each member of the pack must take a small item of personal significance and a length of his or her own hair and give it to the ritemaster. She then binds together all the objects using the hairs and buries the bundle within the pack’s home caern.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">The ritemaster’s player rolls Charisma + Rituals (difficulty 9 minus the pack alpha’s Leadership). If the roll succeeds, the entire pack gains two extra points of Willpower at the beginning of each session as long as the pack alpha is acting in the best interests of the whole pack. (Note that this cannot put a character over their maximum Willpower.) However, if the alpha has not been acting in the pack’s interests, the entire pack loses two points of Willpower at the beginning of each session. The gain or loss is entirely at the Storyteller’s discretion. Should the pack alpha change, the rite’s effects immediately end.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of the Omega Wolf"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">45</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of the Omega Wolf (3)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">punishment</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">3</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField">215</field><field name="description" type="TextField">Some tribes and septs takes the failure of a pack alpha very seriously indeed. If all the members of a pack agree that their alpha has failed them catastrophically, then they may enact this rite to formally reject his leadership and punish his incompetence. The pack takes their fallen alpha and sits him on a rock. They then crown him with a mock crown and bow down in pretend obeisance to him. They then stand up and commence mocking him one by one, before tearing the crown from his head and casting him to the ground. When each member of the pack has spat or urinated on the fallen alpha, the rite is done.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Standard roll. The fallen alpha loses four points of Honor Renown and two points of Wisdom Renown. If he ever becomes a pack alpha again, he suffers a –3 penalty to all Leadership actions until he either relinquishes the position or wins some great victory for his pack through his leadership.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of the Opened Bridge"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">24</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of the Opened Bridge (4)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">caern</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">4</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField">207</field><field name="description" type="TextField">This rite creates a moon bridge, a shimmering portal serving as a mystical means of transportation between two caerns. Such moon bridges are vital  links among the sacred spaces of Gaia. Once per year, a caern must renew its connection with other caerns to which it wishes to maintain moon bridges. This rite is always held during a moot, and it must be enacted simultaneously by both participating caerns.
The primary requirement to open a moon bridge is a pathstone. Pathstones are found in the Umbra, and they are often the objects of quests. These extraordinarily rare stones resemble flat pearls with the imprint of a wolf’s paw on one side. It is possible to steal a pathstone from a caern, but such a theft is considered blasphemous, and it may well result in war between two septs. The rite establishes (or reestablishes) a spiritual connection between the pathstones of two separate caerns by way of the caerns’ totem spirits. At the rite’s culmination, a moon bridge opens between the two participating caerns. During this time, Garou from both septs can travel between the caerns to join in a wild revel. Moon bridges allow Garou to traverse distances in 1/1000th the normal time required. This rite must be renewed once every 13 moons (roughly a year).</field><field name="system" type="TextField">The roll is Wits + Enigmas (difficulty 8 minus the level of the ritemaster’s caern). If the ritemaster’s pack totem is the same as the totem of the caern, she receives a bonus of three dice to the roll. If the rite was unsuccessful previously, the difficulty level of the rite increases by one. The ritemaster needs to obtain a number of successes equal to the target caern’s level to complete the rite. If the rite succeeds, the moon bridge opens immediately, and the spirit-bond between the two pathstones is established. Moon bridges may now be opened at any time between the two caerns. The bridges may be opened with the Rite of the Opened Caern or the Ragabash Gift: Open Moon Bridge (if performed at the caern). If the rite fails, no moon bridge opens, and the rite must be tried again next year. Moon bridges to the caern may still be opened, but they aren’t as safe as they might be. See page 311 for moon bridge distances.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of the Opened Caern"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">25</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of the Opened Caern (1)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">caern</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">1</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField"></field><field name="description" type="TextField">Each caern has a specific power associated with it, generally of a beneficial nature. Thus, there are caerns of Rage, caerns of Gnosis, Strength, Enigmas, and so on. If a character is knowledgeable enough, she may tap into the caern’s power and use it herself. Doing so is commonly known as “opening” a caern. Such a feat shouldn’t be attempted lightly — Gaia’s sacred places don’t give up their power easily, and failure to harness such power can seriously harm the Garou.

Each caern has its own requirements of the ritemaster. In order to open a caern of Enigmas, a Garou might walk a spiral path while calling out the Greek myth of Persephone; to open a caern of Rage, the Garou might change into Crinos and chant the litany of his ancestors who have fallen in battle against the Wyrm. The key is forging a connection to the particular spirit of the caern.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">To open a caern, the character engages in a resisted, extended test of Wits + Rituals (difficulty 7) against the caern’s spirit, seeking to gain a number of successes equal to the caern’s level. The caern spirit uses the caern’s level as its dice pool (difficulty of the ritemaster’s Gnosis), seeking to gain (Ritemaster’s Willpower) successes. The first party to reach their target number of successes triumphs. If the character wins the test, she can add the caern’s rating to her dice pool when performing actions appropriate to the caern’s focus. If she loses, she takes lethal damage equal to the number of successes by which the caern beat her; a botch makes this damage aggravated.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of the Opened Sky"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">41</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of the Opened Sky (4)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">accord</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">4</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField">205</field><field name="description" type="TextField">By sacrificing something of personal value and dancing a complex rain dance, the ritemaster can beckon great, purifying showers of rain to fall from the skies. This rain cleanses all Wyrm impurities, and can even heal wounds.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">This rite works in much the same way as the Rite of Cleansing, but can encompass an entire caern and those within it. The ritemaster expends only one point of Gnosis to cleanse an area, but for every two additional points he spends, every character within the caern heals one level of damage — even aggravated damage. The difficulty of this rite depends on the level of taint, such as a tainted spirit’s Gnosis rating. Like the Rite of Cleansing, the difficulty of this rite can also be lowered by one if performed at dawn. Beings of the Wyrm and vampires suffer excruciating pain if exposed to this rite, though they are not cleansed or genuinely damaged. To use this rite outside a caern, the ritemaster must spend ten points of Gnosis — a feat only the most potent ritemasters of the Garou are capable of.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of the Questing Stone"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">26</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of the Questing Stone (1)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">mystic</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">1</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField"></field><field name="description" type="TextField">This rite allows the werewolf to find a person or object (but not a location). She must know the name of the object or individual, and must dangle a stone or needle from a thread while concentrating on the item or person sought. Glass Walkers often use maps and substitute a
compass for the traditional stone and thread.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Wits + Rituals (diff 7). If the Garou has a piece of the item or individual (a clipping of hair, a piece of cloth) the difficulty drops by one. The werewolf gains only a sense of the object’s general location, not its exact position.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of the Shrouded Glen"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">27</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of the Shrouded Glen (4)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">caern</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">4</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField">207</field><field name="description" type="TextField">This rite causes an area within the Umbra to become invisible, so that it cannot be seen from any other part of the spirit world. At least five people must participate in this ritual, and they must fast for at least three days to purify themselves. The Uktena, who are particularly adept at this rite, maintain that all participants must come to the rite with their bodies clad only in painted symbols representing earth, air, water, fire, and (for the ritemaster) the spirit world.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">The difficulty of this roll is the caern’s Gauntlet + 4. Any participating Garou can contribute Gnosis to this rite. The participants must spend a total of 10 Gnosis points to make the effect permanent. Otherwise, the number of successes achieved equals the number of hours the Umbral Glen remains hidden. If the area the Garou attempt to hide is larger than the caern itself, the amount of Gnosis required increases by two for each one-mile (1.6 km) radius the participants attempt to enshroud.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of the Totem"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">28</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of the Totem (3)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">mystic</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">3</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField">213</field><field name="description" type="TextField">This rite binds a totem to a group of Garou, joining them together as a pack. During the rite, all werewolves who wish to bind their destinies to a particular totem spirit must coat their eyes with an infusion of saliva and mugwort, tobacco, or a similar substance holy to Gaia and step sideways into the Umbra. In the spirit world, the ritemaster leads the Garou in a hunt for the spiritual spoor left by a totem spirit. Such evidence varies with the spirit, but Garou worthy of the totem’s attention can always find it. Even tracking down the spirit doesn’t guarantee success, for the totem must decide whether the Garou are worthy to become its fosterlings. An undecided totem may require a quest of the supplicants, although one is almost never required if the pack has just completed a Rite of Passage successfully.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Characters must purchase the Totem Background to benefit from this rite. Otherwise, the rite is simply not performed. The roll is standard.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of the Winter Winds"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">29</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of the Winter Winds (2)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">seasonal</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">2</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField">218</field><field name="description" type="TextField">On the longest night of the year, Garou enact this rite as a salute to Helios and an encouragement for him to begin lengthening the days again. Some werewolves believe that if this rite is not performed, the nights will continue to lengthen until Gaia has fallen into a terrible twilight state of perpetual pain. Most modern werewolves consider this mere superstition, but even such skeptics participate enthusiastically in the rite. The Rite of the Winter Winds is rarely the same from sept to sept. European Garou practice a common version that begins with the ritemaster gathering the Garou in a circle around a small bonfire. She then leads the group in an extended howl that begins as a low, rumbling growl and eventually rises to an ululating crescendo. When the ritemaster feels that the tension is at its height, she leaps forward, snatches up a burning branch and runs into the woods. The other Garou follow her, grabbing branches as they go. Running as swiftly as they can, the werewolves make as many frightening and strange noises as possible. This rite is performed both to encourage Gaia’s labor in giving birth to the sun, and to frighten off any minions of the Wyrm that might be lurking about, ready to snatch the newborn sun or harm Gaia as she turns her attention away from the surface world. The ritemaster finally leads the howling pack back to the bonfire, where they hurl their branches into the conflagration. Once the fire is raging, the Garou celebrate with a revel that lasts until dawn, at which time they greet the newborn sun with one last, triumphant howl.</field><field name="system" type="TextField"></field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Rite of the Winter Wolf"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">30</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Rite of the Winter Wolf (3)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">death</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">3</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField">209</field><field name="description" type="TextField">Once a werewolf becomes too wounded or aged to fight with his tribe, he performs this bleak and solemn rite. Upon announcing that he will undergo the rite, the werewolf sits at the center of a gathering of his pack- and sept-mates. The meeting is an onerous, solemn affair during which the Moon Dancers sing hymns of the celebrant’s life and deeds and invoke the spirits for glory in the next world or life. The celebrant then slowly and proudly walks through the closed ranks of the tribe. As he passes his people, they begin howling a dirge similar to that sung during the Gathering for the Departed. Some Garou beat heavy drums or play mournful pipes as the celebrant drags himself to a secluded site where he ends his life, usually with a klaive. Rarely, two werewolves, usually packmates, will perform this rite together, sometimes killing each other simultaneously, although Ahroun may give each other a last fight to finish, with the victor ending his life beside his fallen opponent. Immediately after the suicide, the sept performs the Gathering for the Departed.
Red Talons and Get of Fenris are the staunchest supporters of this rite. It is almost unheard of among the Children of Gaia and Bone Gnawers, who value the knowledge and experience of their aged and wounded.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">The rite is always performed at night, typically under the auspice moon of the departing werewolf. Three other Garou must be present to acknowledge the character’s life and departure. Failure to perform the rite properly is considered an omen that Gaia still needs some final service from the Garou.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Satire Rite"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">32</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Satire Rite (3)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">punishment</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">3</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField">215</field><field name="description" type="TextField">A more serious version of the Stone of Scorn, a Satire Rite is a special song, dance and/ or drama crafted by the Half Moons and Moon Dancers for the sole purpose of ridiculing the offender. This rite is always performed at a moot while the offender sits in full view of the sept. Because the Garou keep careful oral histories, the Satire will be remembered and passed down through the ages. Any werewolf so “honored” loses much renown. Cubs snicker as they sing lewd verses from the rite, and adults will forever use some of the wittier quotes and embarrassing movements from the rite when referring to the offender. While such stories are usually confined to members of the offender’s own sept, Tricksters and Moon Dancers are all too happy to spread the new Satire to any Garou they encounter.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">The difficulty of this rite is the offender’s current Rank + 4. If successful, the offender loses one permanent Rank level (reduce his Renown to the beginning amounts for the next lowest rank). The Garou can earn new renown and rank normally. If this rite fails, the Garou loses nothing, while a botch causes the ritemaster to lose five points of Wisdom as she becomes the object of the rite.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Stone of Scorn"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">52</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Stone of Scorn (2)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">punishment</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">2</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField">214</field><field name="description" type="TextField">The Stone of Scorn is a rock imbued with malicious spirit-personifications of shame, sorrow and the like. Some septs have a permanent Stone of Scorn to which an offender is dragged, although most merely imbue a small stone with such energies. Starting with the ritemaster, this stone passes to each Garou present at the rite. The scorned werewolf is forced by his septmates to sit and watch. As each Garou receives the stone, he carves or paints a symbol of derision or shame onto it while telling a mocking or embarrassing tale about the offending behavior and other flaws of the scorned Garou. Moon Dancers are particularly creative in their verbal portrayals of the miscreant. This rite often lasts all night, with successive stories becoming more and more outrageous and derogatory. Once the night ends, so does the punishment, although the best stories are often whispered behind the offender’s back for some time to come. Such behavior causes the Garou to lose Renown for a time.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Standard roll. The punished Garou usually loses eight points of Honor Renown and two points of Wisdom Renown.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="The Badger's Burrow"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">33</field><field name="code" type="CharField">The Badger's Burrow (4)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">caern</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">4</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField">206</field><field name="description" type="TextField">The guardians of the caerns become so connected to their bawn that they can sense all that goes on within its boundaries. The ritemaster enacting this rite gazes intently into a bowl of water, pool of ink, mirror, or some similar focus. At the same time, the werewolf pours a small amount of witch hazel or other strongly scented astringent (even urine) on the ground in front of her. Any other Garou watching or participating encircle the ritemaster and growl softly in the backs of their throats. Some of the younger Garou (Glass Walkers and Wendigo in particular) enhance the ritual through the use of mild psychotropic drugs, although many werewolves frown upon this practice.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">The celebrant must make a successful Perception + Rituals roll against the given difficulty level. Each success enables the ritemaster (or the caern Warder) to ask one question regarding a defined area. Failure indicates that the Garou sees nothing.
Area (diff)
Small room (5)
Ballroom (6)
House (7)
Acre of land (8)
Small forest (9)</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="The Great Hunt"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">34</field><field name="code" type="CharField">The Great Hunt (2)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">seasonal</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">2</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField">218</field><field name="description" type="TextField">This rite falls on the eve of the summer solstice, or Midsummer, when Helios stays longest in the sky and is thus at the zenith of his influence. The short hours of darkness offer the creatures of the Wyrm little place to hide, and the werewolves respond by holding a sacred hunt. Exactly at midnight, just at Midsummer begins, the ritemaster calls upon Gaia to bring to the attention of the sept a creature or creatures worthy of the Great Hunt. In preparation, the Garou chant, howl, and tell tales of bravery. Also common is a ritual bloodletting, wherein each Garou cuts herself and sheds some of her blood into a large bowl. The mingled blood is then used to paint pictograms on the forehead or breastbone of each of the hunters. At dawn, Gaia sends the waiting sept a sign proclaiming the target of the Great Hunt. This sign may come in any form, from a vision seen by an entranced Wendigo ritemaster to a news story flashing on the screen of an old television in a Bone Gnawer caern. Although the person or creature chosen by Gaia is almost always associated with the Wyrm, Gaia demands on rare occasions that one of her own be sacrificed in the Great Hunt. Only the greatest warriors are ever chosen as the targets of a Great Hunt, and Gaia demands such a sacrifice from her children only in times of great need, for the freed spirit of such a warrior is said to transform immediately into an avenging angel for Gaia.  
The Garou have only until midnight to complete the Great Hunt. If successful, the blood of the fallen creature is spilled onto Gaia’s soil (or into the ether if the Great Hunt takes place on the Umbra) as a sacrifice to Gaia. If the hunters fail to slay their quarry, it is considered a terrible omen for the coming year. Some Theurges say that no sept will succeed at the Great Hunt during the year of the Apocalypse. At the least, a failed Great Hunt means poor luck for the sept in the year to come. Anyone participating in a successful Great Hunt gains Glory. The danger of the particular Great Hunt determines the amount of Glory gained.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Characters participating in a successful Great Hunt gain — presuming the target is of average threat level — three points of Glory Renown. If the Great Hunt is unsuccessful, each participating character loses two points of Glory Renown. In addition, the difficulty levels of all rites performed by the sept increase by one until the next Midsummer.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="The Hunt"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">35</field><field name="code" type="CharField">The Hunt (3)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">punishment</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">3</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField">215</field><field name="description" type="TextField">The Hunt is called against a werewolf who has committed a capital crime such as unwarranted murder, yet who still retains a vestige of honor. All Garou participating in a Hunt streak their bodies with ancient symbols in paint or clay. These symbols mark the werewolves as part of a Hunting Pack, and all other Garou will make way for Hunters so marked. It is an honor to be chosen for inclusion in a Hunt. The ritemaster, or Master of the Hunt, leads the pack. The Hunt is just that; the criminal is hunted down and killed by the pack. There is no quarter given, although (for what it’s worth) death exculpates the condemned Garou. Many tragic stories tell of a werewolf forced to choose between violating his word and committing a grave crime. Such Garou, so the stories go, chose to honor their word and were Hunted, but displayed such valor during their last stand that they gained much posthumous renown.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">This rite can be roleplayed using the tracking rules given on page 284.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="The Long Vigil"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">56</field><field name="code" type="CharField">The Long Vigil (3)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">seasonal</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">3</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField">219</field><field name="description" type="TextField">This rite marks the autumnal equinox, when the season of long days gives way to the season of long nights. Although summer is the traditional season of war among many human cultures, the Garou know that their shadow war will be all the more difficult during the lengthening hours of darkness. To prepare themselves, they hold the Long Vigil, a rite designed to sharpen their appetite for the battles ahead. The Long Vigil begins at sundown, around a raging bonfire (some urban caerns make substitutions). The sept spends the day before the Vigil bedecking the caern with trophies of war collected during the previous year. From bent rifles and shredded flak jackets to broken Wyrm-fetishes and strings of teeth, to the skulls of Wyrmish monsters, to smeared blood mixed with the dust of vampires, all manner of mementos adorn the heart of the caern. As the sun slips below the horizon, the ritemaster begins to chant praise to Helios, thanking him for his blessings during the summer, and praying for his safety in the coming winter. The ritemaster then praises Luna and beseeches her aid in the long nights to come. To aid in the ritemaster’s plea for aid, the Galliards of the sept come forward and begin to recite tales of the most glorious battles of the last year and the deeds done in her name. They point to each trophy in turn to tell the story of how it was won from its owner. Particularly eloquent members of other auspices who distinguished themselves in the previous year are sometimes allowed the honor of being the first to tell their own tales. Once the Galliards have finished, the other members of the sept begin to recount their own versions of the great deeds of the previous year. The tale-telling lasts all night; as dawn approaches, the ritemaster invokes Luna one final time. He dedicates all the deeds of the previous year to Luna, her brother Helios, and her sister Gaia, and he promises that the year to come will be just as glorious with Luna’s blessing. As the rite concludes, the Garou hurl as manytrophies as possi</field><field name="system" type="TextField"></field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="The Rending of the veil"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">53</field><field name="code" type="CharField">The Rending of the veil (4)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">punishment</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">4</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField">216</field><field name="description" type="TextField">Sometimes known as Actaeon’s Folly, this rite is used to punish a human who offends the Garou greatly. The offense doesn’t have to be against the Garou per se, but it may be any act against Gaia or Her children. This rite drops the Veil, forcing a human to see and remember the Garou for the duration of an all-night hunt. The ritemaster leaves a small bag of burning dung and herbs near the sleeping victim. When the victim awakens, the Veil has been burned away from his mind. The following hunt may or may not end in the human’s death. Those humans left alive are often rendered insane, as their unprepared minds are unable to accept the truth revealed by the rite. Some few, however, overcome their fear and heal. This rite is not considered a breach of the Litany.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">The ritemaster must place the specially prepared bag of dung and herbs within 10 feet of where the victim sleeps. The bag smolders when the ritemaster performs the rite. The ritemaster doesn’t need to be near the bag to enact the rite. Failure leaves the Veil intact. A botch causes the Garou herself to fall under the Delirium for one night.</field></object><object model="collector.rite" pk="Voice of the Jackal"><field name="refcode" type="IntegerField">36</field><field name="code" type="CharField">Voice of the Jackal (2)</field><field name="path" type="CharField">punishment</field><field name="level" type="PositiveIntegerField">2</field><field name="creature" type="CharField">garou</field><field name="page" type="CharField">214</field><field name="description" type="TextField">When a werewolf’s behavior has shamed not just herself, but her entire sept or tribe, then this rite may be called. When the ritemaster performs this rite, he blows a handful of dust or ashes onto the offender and speaks the following: “Because thy (cowardice/ gluttony/ selfishness/etc.) has proved thee to be of jackal blood, let thy voice proclaim thy true breed!” As the dust and words envelop the punished Garou, her voice changes. Thereafter, she will speak in an annoyingly shrill and piercing nasal whine until the ritemaster repeals the punishment.</field><field name="system" type="TextField">Jackal-hounds, as such punished Garou are known, subtract two dice from all Social rolls. They also lose two points of Glory Renown and five points of Honor Renown. The ritemaster can repeal this punishment at any time, although it may be made permanent for particularly serious crimes (and the Renown loss always remains). Certain jackal-hounds have reclaimed their true voices by completing a quest of great benefit to Gaia.</field></object></django-objects>